Karthik S Kumar

Senior Software Engineer - Collect.chat, Bengaluru

Tel: +91 9744252268 Email: karthikvillanchira@gmail.com

WORK EXPERIENCE - Past 3 Jobs

Collect.chat - Remote

February 2019 - Present

- Redesigned the backend architecture to limit the downtime.
- Developed the new chatbot with a smaller bundle size.
- Implemented a meeting booking widget for the chatbot with Google calendar integration.
- Integrated multiple 3rd party applications to the platform.
- Developed workspace and multi user management system.
- Implemented CI/CD Pipelines
- Designed and developed <u>reach.at</u> which was the top 4th product of the day in ProductHunt

Qburst Technologies - Trivandrum, IN

April 2018 - February 2019

- Responsible for developing the backend for Digital Tips
- Automated fund transfer from the main account to a user account at preconfigured intervals.
- Designed and developed an onboarding platform for companies with Stripe payment gateway support using React and Nodejs.

Wandertrails Pvt Ltd - Bangalore, IN

April 2017 - April 2018

- Built a CRM module to handle travel bookings and send invoices.
- Built a server-side rendering service for AngularJS for better SEO.
- Developed partner pages and coupon handling APIs.

EDUCATION

Cochin University of Science and Technology, Cochin, India

B.Tech Computer Science and Engineering - 2013 - 2017

PROJECTS

Surveyjoy - surveyjoy.co

Pluggable survey bots that can be integrated into any websites to carry out surveys measure customer happiness through NPS surveys.

GitX - gitxapp.com

Designed an open-source chrome plugin to add private notes in GitHub. Built a website for the plugin.

Summary

Fullstack engineer with **3.5+** years of experience. Currently working on a B2B SAAS conversational platform.

ReactJs - **2+** years NodeJs - **3+** year Angular - **1** year

Tech Experience

Node.js | AntDesign | React |
MongoDB | Angular 2+ |
Webpack | git | Redux |
HTML5 | HTTP | JavaScript |
OAUTH2 | CSS3 | AWS |
TypeScript | REST | Nginx |
Puppeteer | Serverless |
Docker | Redis | CI/CD |
PostgreSQL | Stripe | Chrome
APIS | Stripe | Google
Firebase | Swagger

Blog / Relevant Links

My Website:

https://karthikk.xyz

Product Hunt:

https://www.producthunt.com/@itskarthik

My Blog:

https://medium.com/@karthik villanchira

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/karthikvillanchira

Github:

https://github.com/00karthik

Stackoverflow:

https://stackoverflow.com/users/6087555/karthik